# Habteab Firezgi

832-206-8163 <u>firezgihabteab77@gmail.com</u> 1501 Almaden express way, Sanjose, CA, 95125

#### JAVASCRIPT DEVELOPER

Dynamic and passionate front-end web developer with more than 4 years of experience in building responsive websites and mobile applications. Possess a strong work ethic and the ability to adapt to everchanging environments. Effective collaboration skills, team building capabilities, and leadership in diverse and complex operations. Education as well as experience in comprehensive problem solving, creative troubleshooting, and complex project management.

Languages: JavaScript ES6, Node.is, PHP

Web: HTML5, CSS(Flex box, Grid systems), HTTP, Bootstrap, JSON, SPA, jQuery, HTTP Requests,

Fetch API,WP

Frameworks: React, React Native, Expess.js

Database: MongoDB

Web Services: RESTful, JSON

Tools: Visual Studio Code, Collaborative Git

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## Bitwise Industries/AlphaWorks (Sep 2021- present)

- Developed UI workflows and wireframes
- Built feature templates in React and React-native using Redux
- Collaborated with QA, Cyber security, and Ux teams to build, test and maintain responsive applications
- As a team we worked remote using Git-hub and git flow
- Worked on frontend and backend JavaScript based web applications
- Co-teach react classes bitwise boot camp

## Liya Enterprise COMPANY, Asmara, Eritrea (Jan 2019-Feb 2021)

Develops web, software, Applications for clients such as hospitals, hotels, and educational institutions.

## Web Developer

Designed modules, and custom frameworks to support the operations of diverse organizations in the financial, banking, e-commerce, and health domains.

## **Tasks Performed:**

- Participated in breakdown and planning of module structures and project deliverables.
- Contributed to all phases of the Software Development Life Cycle using Agile/Scrum and Waterfall.
- Developed enterprise-level applications using RESTful web services.
- Implemented MVC architecture for separation of concerns. Supported internationalization.
- Designed Responsive and user-friendly interfaces using HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, jQuery, JS, AJAX, React, Redux.

# Habteab Firezgi

832-206-8163 <u>firezgihabteab77@gmail.com</u> 1501 Almaden express way, Sanjose, CA, 95125

#### **Achievements:**

- Improved performance and functionality by debugging and testing code.
- Gained specialized expertise in RESTful web services.
- Ensured timely completion of complex projects despite challenging deadlines.
- Improved new features and modules and optimized existing code.
- Consistently improved quality and delivery standards during software solution development.
- Received a financial bonus for excellent performance.

**Technologies Used:** REST, Express, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, jQuery, Bootstrap, React, Node.js, Express,PHP,WP

## **EDUCATION**

Asmara University
Asmara, Eritrea Sep 1997 to Jul 2001:
Bachelor of Arts in Economics and Finance

De Anza College Cupertino, CA October 2017 to July 2019 Pursued Associated degree in Computer Science

Evangadi Networks
San Jose, CA Feb 2021 to Aug 2021:
Full stack web development Boot Camp